HARUNA SALAMI

samlak1999@gmail.com | +2348068881506 | devsamlak.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/devsamlak

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A detail-oriented Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in software and AI application development. Successfully developed projects from scratch to large-scale user adoption, notably Penmaniacs, and enhanced user acquisition and engagement for platforms like Venngage by half a million users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PENMANIACS

December 2022 – Present

Software Engineer

- Built an AI-driven platform from the ground up that now serves thousands of users.
- Engineered a design system that improved the development speed for new components by 40%.
- Developed a prompt engineering system that increased the academic content quality score by 30%.
- Optimized AI prompts to enhance the model performance, leading to a 20% increase in user engagement.

Technology used: Prompt Engineering, Next JS, React JS, Node JS, Javascript, MongoDB, and Tailwind CSS.

VENNGAGE, Canada.

May 2021 – March 2023

Software Engineer

- Worked with the marketing team in redesigning the platform to increase traffic and make it user-friendly.
- Developed and integrated WCAG-compliant tools for accessible design, resulting in a 25% increase in the platform's adoption by designers focused on accessibility.
- Contributed to driving website traffic to 24 million visits, and onboarding 500,000 users.

Technology used: React JS, Redux, Javascript, Chakra UI, SASS, Storybook, Trello, and PHP.

FREELANCING

December 2019 – April, 2021

Freelance Software Developer

- Automated data scraping for a UK-based analytics firm, reducing manual data collection time by 85% and scraping over 20,000 products.
- Developed an investment tracking platform for Bitclout, increasing the efficiency of portfolio management.
- Built a smart contract and decentralized application for a blockchain-based crowdfunding platform.

Technology used: React JS, Javascript, Node JS, Solidity, Hardhat, Ether JS, and Tailwind CSS

8-OUBE.

March 2019 – December 2019

Software Engineer

- Led software design, development, and deployment of a user-friendly inventory management solution.
- Automated inventory updates, increasing data accuracy by 30% and streamlining operations.

Technology used: PHP, MySQL, Laravel, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

EDUCATION

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, AKURE

2015 - 2021

Bachelor of Technology (4.64/5.00)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won the 2023 Soonami Hackathon by developing an AI-powered platform that simplifies the startup journey for entrepreneurs.
- Won the 2021 Naija SDGs Hackathon by building an investment platform for solar energy projects.
- My startup MyLodge was among the 100 startups selected for the 2019 Startup Istanbul Demo Day.